Today started out well.
いい一日になりそうだった
けど……
集会から帰る時は最悪だった
But after the meeting tonight,
my feelings were hurt.
Earlier in the week, we invited
some friends over to watch a movie.
この間 友人たちと一緒に
映画を見たことを—
And apparently,
どうやら聞いたらしい
this new young elder heard about it,
わたしより年下で新米の長老が—
so he counseled me about it
after the meeting,
集会の後 近づいてきた
saying that I should give
my movie choices
もう少し考えて
映画を選ぶようにだって？
some thought.
I just didn’t like
the way he gave the counsel.
言い方が気に食わない
He’s only 27.
まったく まだ27 年下だぞ
That’s too young.
The next day,
we had plans to go out in the ministry
次の日 カン兄弟と奥さんと
一緒に奉仕する予定があって—
with Brother Kang and his wife.
出かけたものの—
But the motivation
奉仕する気になれない
just wasn’t there.
I asked to speak
with Brother Kang alone.
カン兄弟に時間をいただいて
あったことを話した
I told him what happened
and how we didn’t feel
the counsel applied to us.
あの助言は見当違いだとも伝えた
I can understand
how you might feel.
気持ちは分かりますよ
But, Byong Soo,
けど ビョンス—
be absolutely honest with me.
正直に考えてみて 助言を受けた理由
全く何も思い当たらないでしょうか？
Do you feel there is no valid reason
for that counsel?
Mm.
うーん
Well, maybe there were some scenes
あの映画 ちょっと暴力シーンが
出てきたかもしれないです
that could have been less violent.
But the way he gave the counsel
けど こっちの気持ちを全然聞かないで
助言したんです
—he didn’t even ask how we felt.
Byong Soo, what is the only way
ビョンス いつも完璧に
アドバイスできる人っていますか？
for us to receive perfect counsel?
From a perfect man.
いないですね
That’s right.
そうです
イエスに会いたくても 会えないですね
And is Jesus here on the earth today?
He was right.
それはそうだ
Counsel can only be perfect
いつも完璧にアドバイスできるのは
完璧な人だけだ
if it’s given from a perfect person.
Still, this counsel
about our movie choices
けど 映画をよく選ぶように
というような話は—
would have been so much easier
カン兄弟みたいな もっと年上の
経験のある人から言われたら—
if it came from someone older
and more experienced,
like Brother Kang.
聞く気になれる
Well, he must have sensed
what I was thinking
兄弟はわたしの思いを察したようで—
because he helped me to remember
聖書から一つの話をしてくださった
something from the Bible.
When Job underwent severe trials,
ヨブが大変な経験をしていた時—
it was the younger Elihu who helped Job
ヨブの間違った考えを正したのは
年下のエリフだった
adjust his thinking correctly.
ヨブはプライドを捨てて—
It required humility on Job’s part
年下で 経験の浅い人のアドバイスを
聴いたんだ
to listen to someone younger
and less experienced.
箴言 19章20節を読んでくれた
He then read Proverbs 19:20:
“Listen to counsel and accept discipline,
“助言に聴き従い
懲らしめを受け入れよ”
“それは 将来
あなたが賢くなるためである”
in order to become wise in your future.”
そうか
The point was clear:
アドバイスした人ではなく
アドバイスそのものに心を向けないと！
Keep our focus on the counsel,
not the counselor.
I later shared
Brother Kang’s comments with my wife.
妻とカン兄弟が言ってくれたことを
話し合って気づきました
We both realized that we should welcome
エホバから来ているアドバイスは
すべて受け入れなければ—
all counsel from Jehovah.
It’s for our good.
わたしたちのためのアドバイス
だからです
I’m sure it took courage
きっと兄弟 若いから勇気を出して
近づいてくれたんだろうなあ
for that young elder
to approach me about the matter.
But I’m so glad he did because,
本当に感謝しています
in the end, his counsel
いただいた助言は エホバから
愛されている証拠だったのです
was just another example
of God’s love.